# MICHAEL BUBB

Phone: +1.646.783.8769

Email: michael.bubb@gmail.com LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/mpbubb GitHub: github.com/mbubb

#### **PROFILE**

Linux Systems Engineer with 10 years of root on enterprise Linux environments. I have specialized in datacenter buildouts including Hadoop clusters, Netezza analytics subnets and Aerospike clusters. I am looking to build upon my automation and datacenter management skills.

#### INDUSTRY EXPERIENCE

#### Systems Engineer 2014- OnDeck New York, NY.

- Linux Systems CentOS and Ubuntu
- Ansible configuration
- Postgresql support
- Netezza administration
- Hadoop administration

### **Operations Engineer** 2010–2014

Collective New York, NY.

- General Linux System Administration CentOS and Ubuntu
- Datacenter management
- Hadoop buildout and support
- Netezza administration
- Automation Cobbler; Puppet; Razor; Ansible
- DNS administration
- Bash and Python scripting
- git and github code management
- monitoring with Nagios; Boundary; Circonus; Catchpoint

### **Systems Administrator** 2006-2010

Shipco Hoboken, NJ.

- Linux and UNIX System Administration
- Debian Firewall and Samba installation and configuration
- backup management on 75 servers
- Basic configuration and setup Cisco 26xx routers and HP Procurve 25xx switches
- Organized and carried out Datacenter move of all company servers
- Datacenter management
- Responsible for purchasing and billing authorization
- Help Desk Management for a 700 employee, 50 office global company

## **Junior System Administrator** 2005-2006

Stevens Institute of Technology, Hoboken, NJ.

While enrolled at Stevens in Computer Science I worked as a UNIX System Administrator in the NetBSD Computer lab as well as on a Beowulf Cluster.

#### Network and Systems Administration (Consultant) 2000-2005 optPart, New York, NY.

- Setup networks and practice management systems for lawfirms and veterinary clinics in NYC and Northern NJ.
- Handled legal discovery/ litigation management for lawfirms.
- website hosting on a RedHat server at Datapipe.

#### Curriculum and Teaching Manager 1995-1999 [Berlitz Korea][] Seoul, Korea.

- On a team that opened the first school in the Korean market.
- Hired, trained and managed teachers.
- Developed curricula for clients in Korea including: Samsung, Korean Air, KPMG Korea, P&G and LG.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **Degree**

- BA English, minor in Political Science from Rutgers University, New Bruswick (1992).

#### **Nonmatriculated**

- 40 credits Computer Science, **Stevens Institute of Technology**, Hoboken, NJ (2005-2006).
- 48 credits Comparative Literature, PhD program, NYU, New York, NY (1993-1995).

#### ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

- 2013-present technical volunteer, Milemesh.
- 2012-present emergency shelter and communications, Hoboken CERT.
- 2004-2006 webmaster; editor, **NonServiam Press**.
- 1999-2004 webmaster; editor, The Brooklyn Rail.
- 1989-1991 prep cook; garde manger, **Frog and the Peach**.